* Academic
    
    Academic
    
    * K-5 Subjects
        
        K-5 Subjects

    * AP Subjects
        
        AP Subjects

    * Business
        
        Business

    * Humanities
        
        Humanities

    * Languages
        
        Languages

    * Learning Differences
        
        Learning Differences

    * Math
        
        Math

    * Science
        
        Science

    * Tech & Engineering
        
        Tech & Engineering

    * Popular Subjects
        
        Popular Subjects

    * Learning Membership
        
        Learning Membership

    * About Tutoring
        
        About Tutoring

* Test Prep
    
    Test Prep
    
    * K-8 Exams
        
        K-8 Exams

    * High School Exams
        
        High School Exams
        
        * AP
            
            AP

    * College Entrance Exams
        
        College Entrance Exams
        
        * ACT
            
            ACT

        * SAT
            
            SAT

    * Graduate School Entrance Exams
        
        Graduate School Entrance Exams
        
        * GRE
            
            GRE

    * Certifications & Licenses
        
        Certifications & Licenses
        
        * Finance
            
            Finance

        * Medical
            
            Medical

        * NCLEX
            
            NCLEX

        * Securities
            
            Securities

* Enrichment
    
    Enrichment

    * Coding
        
        Coding

    * Languages
        
        Languages

* For Schools
    
    For Schools

* About
    
    About

Get Started [We're Open, Call Now Call Now **(888) 888-0446**](tel:+18888880446)

Get Started

Privacy Notice
--------------

EFFECTIVE: Jan 3 2024

This Privacy Notice (the “Privacy Notice”) governs the manner in which Varsity Tutors LLC, and its related and affiliated entities, unless otherwise stated or otherwise governed by such entity’s own privacy notice (“Varsity Tutors”) collects, uses, maintains, and discloses information collected from users (each, a “User”) of its [www.varsitytutors.com](https://www.varsitytutors.com/) website, applications, and technology platform, and any derivative or affiliated websites on which this Privacy Notice is posted, linked, or referenced (collectively, the “Site”). The Site is owned and operated by Varsity Tutors. Please note that this Privacy Notice covers Varsity Tutors’ practices regarding information collected from/through its Site. Please read this Privacy Notice carefully to understand how we handle your information. By using the Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Notice. You shouldn’t use the Site if you don’t agree with this Privacy Notice or any other agreement that governs your use of the Site.

The Information Varsity Tutors Collects and Receives
----------------------------------------------------

The categories of information that are collected will depend upon the nature of your interaction(s) with Varsity Tutors and the Site. Below are examples to help you better understand the data we collect.

**Information you provide to us.** We collect a variety of information that you provide directly to us in connection with your use of the Site. While parts of the Site may not require you to provide any information that can directly identify you (such as if you choose to browse the website without logging in), the specific types of information we collect will depend upon how you use the Site and the information you choose to provide. The types of data we collect directly from you include:

**Contact information.** When you submit an inquiry through the Site, we collect your name, email address, and phone number if provided, along with general information about the nature of your inquiry. When you create an account through the Site, we will also collect your username, password, mailing address, and other information related to providing you services through the Site.

**Payment information.** If you make a purchase with us, we (or our business partner(s) who process payment transactions for us) may collect your billing or other financial information in order to process the transaction(s). If you are a contracted tutor, instructor, expert, or educator (collectively, “Professionals”) through the Site, then we (or our business partner(s) who process payment transactions for us) will collect bank account or other financial information in order to facilitate payments to you based upon invoices you submit through the Site and in conjunction with your signed independent contractor agreement(s). Please note that for security we do not store sensitive cardholder data, such as full credit or debit card numbers, card authentication data, or sensitive bank account information.

**Personal, professional, and education-related information.** Professionals who seek to enter into independent contractor agreements with Varsity Tutors or its related and/or affiliated entities are asked to provide additional personal information in support of the Professional’s respective skills and experience, as well as a social security number or taxpayer identification number for tax purposes and government-issued identification, as necessary to facilitate payment and to comply with legal obligations. Professionals also have choices about the information the Professional chooses to include on the Professional’s profile on the Site once under contract, such as education, work experience, skills, city or area, likes or interests, photo, etc. We may also receive criminal history information about Professionals who undergo the background check process, which is administered by external third party vendor(s) that specialize in criminal background checks. Please note that for security we do not collect or store background check information. Customers may also share personal, professional, and education-related information in connection with their requests for tutoring through the Site.

**Student data.** Varsity Tutors for Schools LLC (“VTS”) is an affiliate of Varsity Tutors that contracts with Schools, School Districts, and other local or state education agencies across the US (“Schools”). In conjunction with those agreements between VTS and Schools (“School Agreement(s)”), we may collect and have access to certain personal data of School students that, alone or in combination, is linked or is linkable to a specific student (“School Data”) who has access to the Site through the agreements with Schools. Varsity Tutors or VTS shall only collect and use School Data for the purposes of providing the services set forth in the respective School Agreement(s). General terms between VTS and Schools are set forth [here](https://www.varsitytutors.com/school-solutions/terms). School Data excludes (a) anonymized or aggregated data, and (b) information collected by Varsity Tutors and VTS outside of the services provided to Schools, and Varsity Tutors and VTS may use and maintain such data that is not School Data for its own purposes, including, without limitation, analytics and development purposes, and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Information you submit or otherwise provide or authorize us to collect, which may include voice and likeness information.** We collect the information you post or submit on/through the Site. This includes comments, reviews, documents, questions, chats, messages, assessments, videos, or photos. Such shared content may be publicly viewable by others depending on where it is posted, shared, or viewed. We also collect any other information you may provide to us or authorize us to collect, including any other identifier that permits the ability to contact you. If you communicate with Varsity Tutors or its affiliates by e-mail; post messages to forums; make telephone or cell phone calls or texts; communicate through electronic devices or other interactive devices; complete online forms, surveys, sweepstakes, or contest entries; or communicate with Varsity Tutors or its affiliates by any means, any information provided in such communication may be collected by Varsity Tutors.

**Information about third parties that you provide to us.** A User may also provide personally identifiable information about others, such as emergency contact information for notification in the event a situation requires it, or, if you choose to use our referral service to refer a friend to our Site, then you may provide your referral’s name and email address, as further detailed in the Refer-A-Friend section below. If you submit any personal information about another individual to us, then you are responsible for making sure that you have the authority to do so and to allow us to use their personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

**Information through surveys, testimonials, comments, reviews, and blogs.** You may decide to participate in a survey, to provide a review, to provide a testimonial, to comment on a blog or social media post, etc. If you decide to participate or comment, then you may provide certain information that may include personal information. In addition, we may post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Site that may contain personally identifiable information; however, if/when that happens, we obtain the person's consent via email or other means prior to posting the testimonial, which authorizes us to post certain information along with their testimonial. We may invite you to complete a survey or participate in a promotion, either through the Site or through a third-party platform. If you participate, we will collect and store the data you provide as part of participating. That data is subject to this Privacy Notice unless otherwise stated in the official rules of the promotion or survey, including notifying winners and distributing rewards. Where we use a third-party platform to administer a survey or promotion, the third party’s privacy policy will apply.

**Passively-collected information.** We collect certain information as you visit or interact with our Site, such as the following:

**Internet and electronic network activity information, such as device and usage information.** We may collect information about your browser type, language preference, referring site, subsequent site, and date/time of each visitor request. The purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Users use the Site. We may collect information about your operating system, Internet Service provider information and IP addresses and other device identifiers, such as mobile device information. In addition, we may collect information about your use of the Site, unique views, originating sites, etc., including through the use of tracking technologies (See section pertaining to Tracking Technologies for more information). A User browsing the Site without registering an account or affirmatively providing personally identifiable information to Varsity Tutors does so anonymously.

**Analytics information.** We use certain third-party services to assist us in analysis, auditing, research, and reporting regarding the Site. These third parties may use web logs or web beacons, and they may set and access cookies on your computer or other device. In particular, we use Google Analytics to help collect and analyze certain information for the purposes discussed in this Privacy Notice. You may opt out of the use of cookies by Google Analytics at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Demographic information and information about your interests.** We may collect information such as your zip code, gender, age, income, household or lifestyle information, and information about your interests and preferences.

### How We Use Information

Varsity Tutors may use personally identifiable information collected through the Site for the following reasons:

• for the specific purposes for which the information was collected;

• to fulfill a contractual obligation;

• to contact Users regarding Varsity Tutors' live-learning platform;

• to communicate to Users, including regarding products and services offered through Varsity Tutors, its parent, subsidiaries, and trusted affiliates;

• to maintain and improve its products, services, and sites;

• to provide support;

• to enhance Users’ experiences with the Varsity Tutors platform;

• to inform Users of offerings that may be of interest;

• to process payments;

• for business planning, marketing, advertising and sales purposes;

• for information security purposes;

• to defend its legal rights;

• to efficiently maintain its business; and

• to comply with applicable law.

### Information Sharing

We do not permit third party advertising partners to collect information related to School Data.

We may share information that we collect about you in the following ways:

**With our service providers and third-party vendors.** We contract with select third party vendors to provide services on our behalf, for example, services such as email, hosting, cloud storage, maintenance, backup and analysis, communications software, marketing, business strategy, banking, payment processing, professional services, background checks, etc. We also share non-personal information (such as aggregate user statistics, de-identified information, demographic information, etc.) with third parties such as advertisers, content providers, and analytics providers.

**Within the Varsity Tutors family of companies and brands.** Varsity Tutors may disclose personally identifiable information collected from Users to its parent, subsidiaries, and other related companies, trusted affiliates, independent contractors and business partners who will use the information for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Notice, as necessary to provide the services offered by or through Varsity Tutors and to provide the Site itself, and for the specific purposes for which the information was collected. These companies are not permitted to use your personally identifiable information in any other way. We may also share information with third parties with which we have a commercial relationship, such as an affiliate marketing agreement; however, we do not use School Data for any commercial relationship or purpose other than in conjunction with providing the services to the School consistent with the School Agreement.

**With a Professional related to a student.** In conducting the matching process between a student and a Professional, we may share a student’s information with the Professional who may provide or will be providing tutoring or instruction to the student so that the Professional may evaluate the engagement and personalize and tailor the tutoring/instruction to the student. In each case, we collect such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the User’s interaction with Varsity Tutors. In addition, information may be shared with a School to the extent the student is part of the VTS product offering and it is shared pursuant to and consistent with the applicable School Agreement.

**To the extent required by law or to protect the company or others.** Varsity Tutors may disclose personally identifiable information at the request of law enforcement or governmental agencies or in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, to establish, protect, or exercise Varsity Tutors’ legal or other rights or to defend against a legal claim or as otherwise required or allowed by law. Varsity Tutors may disclose personally identifiable information in order to protect the rights, property, or safety of a User or any other person. Varsity Tutors may disclose personally identifiable information to investigate or prevent a violation by User of any contractual or other relationship with Varsity Tutors or the perpetration of any illegal or harmful activity.

**In connection with any business acquisition, sale, or merger, or in connection with investor relations.** Varsity Tutors may disclose or transfer personally identifiable information collected from Users in connection with or in contemplation of a sale of its assets or business or a merger, consolidation, or other reorganization of its business. Varsity Tutors may also disclose aggregate, anonymous data based on information collected from Users to investors and potential partners.

Users may always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site-related activities.

### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies/Analytics

Varsity Tutors and its analytics and marketing providers use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts (collectively “cookies”), to analyze trends, administer the Site, track Users’ movements around the Site, and to gather demographic information about our User base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. Varsity Tutors does not place tracking technologies related to targeted advertising on areas of the Site directed to students who are accessing the Site under a School Agreement.

We use cookies for tracking page view/usage (log data), estimating audience size and usage patterns, services metadata, device information, location information, saving Users’ preferences and settings information, advertising new content that relate to your interests, keeping track of advertisements and search engine results, and for authentication. Each User can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level by adjusting your browser settings. Please see the links here for guidance on how to modify your web browser’s settings on several popular browsers: [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en), [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/safari/sfri11471/mac), [Microsoft Edge](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/delete-cookies-in-microsoft-edge-63947406-40ac-c3b8-57b9-2a946a29ae09), [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/description-of-cookies-ad01aa7e-66c9-8ab2-7898-6652c100999d), and [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enhanced-tracking-protection-firefox-desktop?esab=a&s=cookies&r=6&as=s&redirectslug=enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences&redirectlocale=en-US).

If you choose to block all cookies (including essential cookies), you may still use our Site, but your ability to use some or all features or areas of our Site may be limited. To find out more about cookies and similar technologies, visit the Varsity Tutors [Cookie List](https://www.varsitytutors.com/cookie-list), [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/), [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/), or [https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/).

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, clickstream, and/or field input data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you and to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

We implement Google Analytics features that use display and/or digital advertising information for Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. You can read more about the cookies used by Google Analytics advertising features, by going to the Google Analytics Privacy Notice page, linked here. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, to prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics, by going to the Google Analytics opt-out page. We also use Facebook Analytics. You can opt out of Facebook Analytics by following the instructions in its Data Policy and Cookies & Other Storage Technologies section.

We, along with third-party vendors (including Google), use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics and Facebook Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookies) to report how your ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to our website.

### LSOs

Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to digital advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs, which can be accessed through the web browser links referenced above.

### Behavioral Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. Please note that behavioral targeting does not apply to students who are accessing the Site under a School Agreement. You can manage your preferences for these advertising programs through the following links: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/ads), [Google](https://myadcenter.google.com/home?hl=en&sasb=true&ref=ad-settings), [Bing](https://about.ads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads), and [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out). Please note this would not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Social Media Widgets

Certain portions of the Site include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Your Choices Regarding Your Information

In addition to your choices outlined above related to cookies, browser, and analytics preferences, you also have choices regarding the following:

**Updating your account information:** If you have an account, you may be able to review the information you provided to us by logging into your account page and adjusting the settings under the “Account” tab. If there is additional information that you believe needs to be updated, please let us know by completing the form linked [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html).

**Email communications:** If you receive an unwanted email from us, you can update your preferences by accessing the email preferences in your account settings page, or you can use the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of the email to opt out of future emails; however, please note that you will continue to receive transaction-related emails regarding products or services you have requested. You may also submit a request to us [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html).

**Telephone/Text communications:** If you receive an unwanted call or message from us, you can update your phone preferences by accessing your phone preferences in your account settings page, or you can send a Do Not Call request to us at the following email address: [dnc@varsitytutors.com](mailto:dnc@varsitytutors.com). Regarding text messages, you may opt out of SMS by replying “STOP” to the message received.

**Do Not Track and other similar signals:** Some internet browsers incorporate a “Do Not Track” or other similar feature; however, given that there is not a uniform way for browsers to communicate this signal, the Site does not currently support these signals. Global Privacy Control (“GPC”) is a technical specification in your browser settings that you can use to automatically inform websites of your privacy preferences with regard to third party online tracking, and Varsity honors these signals. To find out more about and set up GPC, please visit [https://globalprivacycontrol.org/#about](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/#about).

**Cookies and Internet-based Advertising:** You may stop, restrict, or remove the placement of cookies on your device by adjusting your preferences as your browser or device permits. The online advertising industry also provides websites from which you may opt out of receiving targeted ads from data partners and other advertising partners. These may be accessed at sites such as [www.aboutads.info/choices](https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN), in addition to the links referenced within this Notice above.

**Deletion or Other Request under Applicable privacy laws:** In general, to request deletion of your information or for another request regarding your information, please complete the form request [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe, or otherwise in accordance with applicable law. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. In addition to filling out the above-referenced request form, questions can be emailed to [privacy@varsitytutors.com](mailto:privacy@varsitytutors.com). For jurisdiction-specific information or related rights, please see the jurisdiction-specific sections below.

### Data Retention

We store the information collected as described in this Privacy Notice for as long as you are a User of the Site and/or as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which the information was collected, to provide services through the Site, to resolve disputes, to pursue legitimate business purposes, to enforce our agreements, to establish legal defenses, to prevent fraud, and to comply with applicable laws. These needs can vary based upon the data type and the context of the services, and thus the retention will vary as well. For example, School Data is deleted within ninety (90) days from expiration or termination of the School agreement unless the School has contracted for a different retention schedule.

### Security of Information

Varsity Tutors discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information based upon user consent only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process transactions on our behalf or to provide tutoring services, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. We take all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

Information about each User that is maintained on Varsity Tutors’ systems is protected using industry standard security measures. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@varsitytutors.com](mailto:privacy@varsitytutors.com). However, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable, and Varsity Tutors cannot guarantee that the information submitted to, maintained on, or transmitted from its systems will be completely secure. Varsity Tutors is not responsible for the circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures relating to the Site by any User or third parties.

Your security is a priority and we strive to provide a safe and secure environment for our customers; however, please note that we cannot guarantee that the information submitted to, maintained on, or transmitted from our systems will be completely secure. If you do not feel comfortable sending your financial/credit card over the Internet, contact us and we will be happy to fill your order over the phone.

Students who access the Site pursuant to agreements with Schools do so via portal links provided by their respective School. Most Schools enable single sign on (SSO) through Classlink or Clever, which provides a direct connection to the relevant portion(s) of the Site pursuant to the agreement with the School.

### Links to 3rd Party Sites

Please note that the Site may contain links to other Sites. These linked sites may not be operated or controlled by Varsity Tutors. Varsity Tutors is not responsible for the privacy practices of these or any other Sites, and you access these Sites entirely at your own risk. Varsity Tutors recommends that you review the privacy practices of any other Sites that you choose to visit.

### Blogs

Anytime you post on our blog please be aware that you are posting using a third-party application, and we have no access or control over this information. To request removal of your personal information from any blog, you can either log into the third-party application and remove your comment or you can contact the appropriate third party application. Your interaction with these features is governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Professionals’ Profiles/Bios

If you are contracted as a Professional through the Site, then the profile you create on our Site will be publicly accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile and make it non-public through your account portal, or as otherwise set forth in the terms of your independent contractor agreement.

### Children’s Privacy

Varsity Tutors products are specifically designed to function without third party access to a child’s personal information. Our Site does not collect or retain any personal information from children except as needed to facilitate tutoring for that student, who may be a minor. Varsity Tutors is committed to complying fully with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”) as well as the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”) in conjunction with the VTS offerings - more information can be found at [Terms for Education Offerings](https://www.varsitytutors.com/school-solutions/terms). This Site assures the privacy of collected information in accordance with Varsity Tutors' Privacy Notice.

Varsity Tutors is committed to safeguarding the information each User entrusts to Varsity Tutors and believes that every User should know how it utilizes the information collected from each User. Other than free information and materials that do not require any registrations or identifying information, the Site is not directed at children under 13 years of age, and Varsity Tutors does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age online. For purposes of using the Site as a platform to connect with tutors, Parents may supply information such as name or age of their children in order for Varsity Tutors to assist facilitate the connection between student and tutor. Varsity Tutors may store this information in a secure digital format. Parents or guardians of children under 13 years of age may review or have deleted any personal information previously provided by the child, parent, or guardian that is ultimately collected by Varsity Tutors, if any, to connect the child with a tutor. If you seek to review or delete such information, contact Varsity Tutors at the below phone number or email address indicating what you would like to have done and Varsity Tutors will contact you for purposes of taking the requested action, including but not limited to refusing to permit the information’s further collection or use.

### Refer-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to refer a friend about our Site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting the referral to visit the Site. Varsity Tutors stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Privacy Rights Under Certain U.S. State Laws
--------------------------------------------

**Nevada Residents:** Nevada Revised Statute Section 603A permits a User that resides in Nevada the right to submit a verified request that Varsity Tutors not sell such User’s covered information. Nevada law defines “sale” to mean the exchange of certain types of personal information for monetary consideration to a person for the person to license or sell the information to additional persons. We do not currently sell personal information as defined under Nevada Revised Statute Section 603A. However, if you are a Nevada resident, you may still submit a verified request by completing the request form [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html) to opt out of sales and we will record your instructions and incorporate them in the future if our policy changes. We will verify your request using information associated with your account, including email address, and may need to request additional information.

**California, Colorado, Connecticut, and Virginia Residents:** Subject to certain limitations, the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) and the California Privacy Reform Act (CPRA) provides California consumers and employees the right to: request disclosure about what personal information we collect, use, disclose, and sell; request to delete, access, or modify their personal information; opt out of any “sale” of personal information; and not be discriminated against for exercising such rights. In addition, the Colorado Privacy Act (CPA) and the Connecticut Personal Data Privacy and Online Monitoring Act (CTDPA) provides Colorado and Connecticut consumers, respectively, the right to request disclosure about what information we collect, use, disclose, and sell; request to delete, access, or modify their personal information; opt out of any “sale” of personal information; and not be discriminated against for exercising any such rights. The Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (CDPA) provides Virginia consumers the right to request disclosure about what information we collect, use, disclose, and sell; request to delete, access, or modify their personal information; opt out of any “sale” of personal information; not be discriminated against for exercising such rights; and an ability to appeal the denial of any such request. The Utah Consumer Privacy Act (UCPA) provides Utah consumers the right to request to delete, access, and opt out of certain processing. Persons under the applicable regulations above may make a request pursuant to their rights under the CCPA, CPRA, CPA, CTDPA, CDPA and/or the UCPA by completing the request form [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html). You may also submit a request by emailing [privacy@varsitytutors.com](mailto:privacy@varsitytutors.com).

We will verify your request using information provided in the request form, as compared against information associated with your account, including verification of the email address that was listed in the request form. We may need to request additional information in order to verify your identity. Depending upon the type of request you make, we may require a signed declaration under penalty of perjury stating that you are the individual whose personal information is being requested. If you use an authorized agent to submit a request, we may require that the authorized agent provide proof of your written permission, and that you verify your identity directly with us.

We have explained our privacy practices in full in the foregoing sections of this Privacy Notice. Below we have provided a list of the categories of personal information that have been collected, disclosed for business purposes, or “sold” for commercial purposes (as defined by the CCPA) during the preceding 12 months, as well as certain other information. Please see the other sections of the Privacy Notice above for additional information and context related to the sharing of information. We do not consider the ways we share your personal information to comprise the sale of your information. Within the past 12 months, we may have disclosed the following categories of information about consumers for a business purpose:

Categories of Information and Explanations

Identifiers, such as your name, street address, phone number, IP address, or email address

We use this information to respond to your questions, to communicate with you, for marketing purposes, to enable you to participate in our offerings, and for other business purposes.

Commercial information, such as purchase history

Records of purchases or other histories.

Internet and electronic network activity

We may use this information to improve our services, to better understand the visitors who come to our Site and what content is of interest to them.

Geographic location information

We may use this information to improve the quality, security, and relevance of our services and for other business purposes.

Other electronic information, such as information you post in a public space

We may use this information to provide the services, and for other business services.

Inferences drawn from the above

We use this information to personalize your experience with us, to understand other profile preferences, characteristics, trends, abilities, and aptitudes, and for other business purposes.

International Users, Transfers, and Rights
------------------------------------------

Varsity Tutors is based, and this Site is hosted, in the United States of America. If you are located outside of the United States, then you may be in a location with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law. You understand that by being a User of the Site and/or by entering into an agreement with us as a customer, that you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your data in the U.S. To the extent you are a Professional who uses the Site in an independent contractor capacity to advertise your services to customers/students through the Site, then you understand that your information will be collected, stored, and processed in the U.S. based upon your consent given through your independent contractor agreement.

We rely on different lawful bases for collecting and processing personal data about you depending upon how you use the Site, including your consent, contractual necessity to provide the services and operate the Site and the business, to meet contractual and legal obligations, to protect the security of our systems and our Users, and/or to fulfill other legitimate interests.

Please refer to the Your Choices Regarding Your Information section to review the rights you have regarding your data. Any user may make a request regarding applicable privacy rights by completing the form captured [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html). In addition, your local laws (e.g., in the United Kingdom or Canada) may permit you to request that we: Provide access to and/or a copy of certain information that we hold about you; prevent the processing of your information for direct-marketing purposes; update information that is out of date or incorrect; delete certain information related to you; restrict processing; transfer your information; and/or revoke your consent for the processing of your information. We will consider all requests and will provide a response within the time period required by applicable laws. We may request that you provide us with additional information in order to confirm your identity before responding to your request.

Changes to this Privacy Notice
------------------------------

We may update this Privacy Notice to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, then we may notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. Please review this Privacy Notice periodically. Your continued use of the Site after any such change(s) signifies your acceptance of any changes.

Contacting Varsity Tutors
-------------------------

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, you may contact Varsity Tutors via any of the following methods:

Mail: Varsity Tutors ATTN: Legal, 8001 Forsyth Blvd. Suite 1050, St. Louis, Missouri 63105

Phone: 314-422-2007

Email: [privacy@varsitytutors.com](mailto:privacy@varsitytutors.com)

Information request form: Complete the form [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/ffef8acc-d836-4aba-9461-f5d802e9b675/02cdfd0f-53bd-4020-aeeb-afc84808961e.html).

We are committed to ensuring this Privacy Notice is accessible to individuals with disabilities. If you wish to access this Privacy Notice in an alternative format, please contact us as described above.

Here's what our clients are saying
----------------------------------

#### Parent of 12th grade student

Tanque Verde High School, Tucson, AZ  
_Thank you so much for your help, and for leading your tutor to our daughter. He is not only a remarkable tutor, he was an excellent teacher for our student. Maybe more importantly, our daughter is now armed with the confidence that math is not a hopeless cause, and she really can conquer it. That is a great success story!_

#### Parent of high school student

Houston, TX  
_Thank you very much for the wonderful service that you have provided for Jose. Jose has learned so much from Amy \[our tutor\]. I was very impressed with her and your program. Thanks again and please let Amy know how wonderful she is. I was very impressed._

#### Parent of high school student

Parkway North High School, St. Louis, MO  
_After several tutoring sessions with Kirthika \[our tutor\] right before winter finals, my child was able meet the goal of maintaining an 'A' in Honors Biology and a 'B' in Honors Geometry._

* Varsity Tutors
    
    Varsity Tutors

* Our Company
    
    Our Company

* Free Resources
    
    Free Resources

* Top Subjects
    
    Top Subjects

* Top Locations
    
    Top Locations

* Tutoring By Grade Level
    
    Tutoring By Grade Level

Show More

Canada - English United Kingdom - English US - English

Varsity Tutors © 2007 - 2024 All Rights Reserved

* [Show Disclaimer](javascript:void(0))

Names of standardized tests are owned by the trademark holders and are not affiliated with Varsity Tutors LLC.

Media outlet trademarks are owned by the respective media outlets and are not affiliated with Varsity Tutors.

Award-Winning claim based on CBS Local and Houston Press awards.

Varsity Tutors does not have affiliation with universities mentioned on its website.

Varsity Tutors connects learners with a variety of experts and professionals. Tutors, instructors, experts, educators, and other professionals on the platform are independent contractors, who use their own styles, methods, and materials and create their own lesson plans based upon their experience, professional judgment, and the learners with whom they engage.

¹ Lee, J.Y. (2013). “Private tutoring and its impact on students' academic achievement, formal schooling, and educational inequality in Korea.” Unpublished doctoral thesis. Columbia University.
